Christopher F. Wood Papers VHP2006/18
CCSU Veterans History Project
Christopher F. Wood Papers
Bulk, 1969-1972
1969 - 1972, 2006
VHP2006/18
CCSU Veterans History Project
106.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
This collection details experience of Christopher F. Wood as he served with U.S. Coast Guard during Vietnam War. The collection contains video oral history interview, military records, and photographs.
Wood, Christopher F., (Christopher Francis), 1951 -
Biographical/Historical note
Christopher Wood joined the U.S. Coast Guard on July 14, 1969. He chose the Coast Guard because one of his friends had also enlisted, and he thought the chances of him going to Vietnam would be decreased. He went to the Coast Guard Academy in Cape May, NJ, where basic training lasted eight weeks and the seaman apprentices learned a myriad of skills. Just after finishing basic training, Wood was assigned to Cutter Chase, which was on its way to Vietnam. The cutter's home base was Subic Bay in the Philippines. From there the ships would deploy for 30-day patrols, where it was the Coast Guard's duty to stop the "flow of men and materials" from North Vietnam to South Vietnam. These patrols were known as "Operation Market Time"" Wood was stationed in Vietnam for ten months during which time Cutter Chase completed 7-8 patrols. When Wood returned to the United States, he attended radar school on Governor's Island, NY, and graduated as a petty officer with the title, Radarman. He was then transferred to the Cutter Campbell out of Portland, ME. Wood was discharged from the Coast Guard on August 24, 1972 after four years of service and returned to Connecticut.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
United States. Coast Guard.; USCGC Chase (WHEC-718).; Cape May (N.J.); Governors Island (New York County, N.Y.); Portland (Me.); Subic Bay (Philippines); Vietnam; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Personal narrative, American
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2006/18.I
  - Enlistment Contract - U.S. Coast Guard, 1969; VHP2006/18.I.1
  - Shellback certificate, 1969; VHP2006/18.I.2
  - Shellback Subpoena and Summons Extraordinary, 1969; VHP2006/18.I.3; 2.0 Digital objects
  - Discharge certificate, 1972; VHP2006/18.I.4
  - Record of discharge, release from active duty, or death, 1972; VHP2006/18.I.5
  - DD form 214N, Discharge form, 1972; VHP2006/18.I.6
  - US Navy “Meritorious Unit commendation” award, circa 1972; VHP2006/18.I.7
  - Medals & plaques, n.d.; VHP2006/18.I.8; 6.0 Digital objects
  - Senior Officer Present Aboard (SOPA) discount drinking card at Hong Kong R&R, 1970; VHP2006/18.I.9
  - Sketch of USCGC CHASE (WHCE-718), 1992; VHP2006/18.I.10
  - Interview synopsis, 2006; VHP2006/18.I.11
- Series II: Military Documents, VHP2006/18.II
  - A teletype from the Commander Task Group to USCG CHASE, 1969; VHP2006/18.II.01; 2.0 Digital objects
  - Christopher F. Wood’s Military Records, 1970s; VHP2006/18.II.02; 10.0 Digital objects
- Series III: Publications, VHP2006/18.III
  - WHEC 718 CHASE Familygrams newsletter, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.III.01; 47.0 Digital objects
    General note
    Family grams are newsletters that were sent home to the families of the troops on the USCGC CHASE of the WESTPAC tour in Vietnam, written by the Commander for the U.S. Coast Guard, Wayne E. Caldwell. The Coast Guard Cutter CHASE Association’s history committee took the original family grams that were saved by Christopher F. Wood’s mother and reformatted and edited them.
  - USCGC CHASE, WESTPAC Tour, Ship Roster, n.d.; VHP2006/18.III.02; 7.0 Digital objects
    Reproduced from USCGC CHASE ASSOCIATION website http://www.cgcchaseassoc.org
- Series IV: Multi-Media, VHP2006/18.IV
  - Subseries A: Still Images, VHP2006/18.IV
    - Seaman Apprentice Christopher F. Wood (left) on mess cook duty in USCGC CHASE’s Galley, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.1
    - Seaman Apprentice Christopher F. Wood with South Vietnamese officer interpreter, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.2
    - Seaman Christopher F. Wood holding an M-60 machine gun, standing on the starboard bridge wing USCGC CHASE (WHEC-718), 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.3
    - Seaman Christopher F. Wood (left) with 50 CAL machine gun crew. USCGC CHASE (WHEC-718), 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.4
    - Christopher F. Wood (right) with shipmate. USCGC CHASE (WHEC-718), 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.5
      King post mounted on flight deck used for highlining mail etc. during Underway replenishment can be seen in background
    - Christopher F. Wood with South Vietnamese Interpreter. USCGC CHASE, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.6
    - Deck gun of USCGC CHASE (WHEC-718), 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.7
    - US Navy Helicopter landing on CHASE’S flight deck, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.8
    - Vertical replenishment (vertrep), helicopter from US Navy stores ship bringing food, supplies and mail., 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.9
    - US Army Helicopter landing on CHASE’S flight deck, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.10
    - “Operation Market Time” Junk and sampan inspection. USCGC CHASE (WHEC-718), 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.11
    - USCGC CHASE rescuing Navy yard tug boat 785 which was taking on water during heavy seas, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.12
    - USCGC CHASE rescuing Navy yard tug boat 785 which was taking on water during heavy seas, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.13
    - Navy Yard Tug Boat 785 near USCGC CHASE, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.14
    - US Coast Guard Squadron 3 Vietnam Belt buckle, 1969 - 1970; VHP2006/18.IV.15
    - Christopher F. Wood at the time of interview, Dec. 28, 2006; VHP2006/18.IV.15
  - Subseries B: Moving Images, VHP2006/18.IVb
    - Oral history interview with Christopher F. Wood, Dec. 28, 2006; VHP2006/18.IVb.1; 1.0 dvd (Disk DVD VHP2006/18, Box VHP Interview 2006)